Tanise Williams

Software Engineer

Oakland, CA 94610 (917) 859-7077 tanwill.github.io tanise.williams@icloud.com

ABOUT

As a Software Engineer and Revenue Operations Consultant I am involved in the strategic convergence of technology, data, sales, marketing, and customer success to drive full funnel accountability across the client's revenue engine. I have an emerging skill set in the fields of Artificial Intelligence and Machine Learning, as well as years of experience with Apex, Java, JavaScript, React, Redux, Jest, Node, Salesforce, SQL, SOQL, Agile, Git, and other technologies. I am an analytical, solution driven thinker who prioritizes the advancement of client processes and systems.

EXPERIENCE

Go Nimbly, San Francisco, CA — Software Engineer

July 2019 - PRESENT

- ◆ Revenue Operations Consultant / Full Stack Software Engineer (Apex/Java, React, and Redux).
- ◆ Salesforce Administration, Development, and API Integration.
- ♦ Go Nimbly is a San Francisco-based Revenue Operations industry leader and business stack consultancy. Go Nimbly provides SaaS and other innovative, high-growth companies with the strategies, technologies and operational roles needed to optimize strategic growth and meet the revenue goals of their C-suites and investors.

Ada's List, San Jose, CA — *Member*

March 2020 - PRESENT

◆ Ada's List is a global community for women in tech, based on principles of inclusion, empowerment, and diversity. We're a group of 7500+ women who work in science, technology, engineering, or mathematics.

Women in Revenue, London, England, United Kingdom — *Member*

March 2020 - PRESENT

♦ Women in Revenue is a non-profit organization focused on current and future women leaders in technology, sales, and marketing roles with education, support, and networking opportunities.

PROGRAMMING

Apex / Java JavaScript React Redux Jest Node.js Salesforce

OPERATING SYSTEMS

Macintosh Windows Linux iOS

APPLICATIONS

Google API, Google Docs, Photoshop, Atlassian Jira

OTHER TECHNOLOGIES

Git, Gulp, SQL, SOQL, Visual Studio Code, Vim

University of California, Berkeley, Berkeley, CA — *Software Developer*

January 2019 - July 2019

- ◆ Position with a university affiliated digital agency from January 2019 to July 2019.
- ◆ Building pixel perfect, custom websites to high specifications for an array of clients and organizations, primarily UC Berkeley (haas.berkeley.edu, law.berkeley.edu).
- ◆ Ensuring the technical feasibility of UI/UX designs while optimizing applications for maximum speed and scalability.
- ◆ Assuring that all user input is validated before submitting to back-end.
- ♦ Handling asynchronous requests, partial page updates, AJAX calls, and the Fetch API.

June 2018 - December 2018

- ◆ Contract position with UC Berkeley Public Affairs from June 2018 to December 2018.
- ◆ Developed and modified codebases for University websites (berkeley.edu, news.berkeley.edu, calparents.berkeley.edu, blogs.berkeley.edu) in accordance with branding guidelines.
- ♦ Worked with campus leadership, journalists, and staff to design and implement needed technical features and functionalities.
- ◆ Customized 3rd party analytics software (Chartbeat) with JavaScript and PHP.
- ◆ Converted comprehensive layouts and wireframes into working, responsive features.
- ◆ Prioritized user experience and web accessibility.

Independent Contractor, San Francisco, CA / New York, NY — Front End Developer

January 2016 - PRESENT

- ◆ Provided Front End development services for companies in San Francisco, CA and New York, NY.
- ◆ Analyzed detailed business requirements and provided recommendations for technical developments and implementations.
- ◆ Created and modified consumer-facing web applications by way of content management systems.
- ◆ Coordinated workflow processes while solving issues with object-oriented programming, testing, and cross-browser compatibility.

Lumina, New York, NY — Front End Developer

DECEMBER 2016 - JANUARY 2018

- ◆ Configured servers and imported/exported databases using Apache, PHP, and MySQL.
- ◆ Designed, developed, and built consumer-facing web applications using JavaScript, Node, React, PHP, and model-view-controller (MVC) architecture.
- ◆ Developed mobile-first web pages based on designs while prioritizing user-experience.
- ♦ Worked with project managers to complete tasks for clients using Agile methodology.
- ◆ Utilized Google Maps API to create custom forms for client websites.
- ♦ Initiated and implemented source control, team collaboration tools, and SEO best-practices.

The Berman Group, New York, NY — Front End Developer

JANUARY 2016 - OCTOBER 2016

- ◆ Executed daily email marketing using Photoshop, MailChimp, and Constant Contact.
- ◆ Started servers using Node.js and Bash scripts.
- ◆ Integrated data from various back-end services and databases.
- ◆ Maintained various client sites and web applications.

EDUCATION

Udacity, Mountain View, CA

AI for Business Leaders Executive Program

Issued: May 2020

Credential ID: 2DC9J5M2

Credential URL: https://confirm.udacity.com/2DC9J5M2

Udacity, Mountain View, CA

Machine Learning Engineer Nanodegree

Issued: In Progress

University of North Florida, Jacksonville, FL

Undergraduate coursework towards Bachelor of Science (Psychology).

General Assembly, New York, NY

JavaScript focused workshops and classes.